Guide to the Filippo Tommaso Marinetti Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Letters to and about Filippo Tommaso Marinetti, 1898-1970; Series III; 4.25; (10 boxes)
  - Kahn, Gustave to FTM (Undated Correspondence)
    - n.d. J'ai reçu l'un du Rinascimento... 3 p.; n.d. Aussitôt reçu le n. de Poesia... 3 p.; n.d. Merci la gentil souvenir... 2 p.; n.d. Comme je vous le disais... 5 p.; n.d. J'ai été très pris... 4 p.; n.d. Merci de l'envoie d'Esilio... 1 p.
    - n.d. Pouvez-vous fournir à mon ami... 2 p.; n.d. Tous mes remerciements... 3b p.; n.d. Je suis allé tout récemment voir... 4 p.; n.d. Nous avons reçu votre gâteau... 3 p.; n.d. J'ai parlé à la Revue Blanche... 2 p.; n.d. Ce n'est pas moi l'organisateur... 3 p.; n.d. Nous avons un empêchement... 1 p.
    - n.d. Quand parait le n. de Poesia... 3 p.; n.d. Et ce voyage! J'envoie... 2 p. Accompanied by a list of names on page 3.; n.d. Suis à Lyons et si je ne vous ai pas... 1 p.; n.d. J'ai reçu votre dépêche trop tard... 2 p.; n.d. J'ai bien reçu votre manuscrit... 2 p.; n.d. Mes meilleurs remerciements... 2 p.; n.d. Oui mon cher ami, je suis... 4 p.; n.d. Je suis très heureux que M. Sacchelli... 4 p.
    - n.d. Il y a bientôt trente ans... 2 p.; n.d. C'est avec un vif plaisir... 4 p.; n.d. Nous serons à Paris... 5 p.; n.d. Et ces épreuves? ces épreuves? J'ai... 3 p.; n.d. J'ai été tellement harcelé de... 2 p.; n.d. Je reçois Poesia... 2 p.; n.d. J'envoie mon acceptation à... 2 p.
  - Kahn, Gustave to FTM (Dated Correspondence)
    - 1899 Oct Postcard; [1901 Mar 18] 2 p.; [1901 Apr 30] 5 p.; 1901 Jul 18 Postcard; 1901 Sep Postcard; 1901 Nov 4 Postcard; [1902 Mar 18] 3 p.; [1902 Oct 25] 2 p. (Box 12, Folder 612)
    - 1903 Aug 3 Postcard; 1904 Mar 7 Postcard; 1904 Jun 29 Postcard; 1904 Oct 16 Telegram; [1904 Oct 30] 2 p.; [1905?] Merci de l'aimable article que je reçois... 4 p. pages 2-3 has letter to FTM from Rachel Gustav Kahn.
    - [1905?] Ceci est la lettre particulière... 4 p.; [1905 Jul 9] 4 p.; [1905 Aug 10] 4 p.; [1905 Oct 8] 3 p.; [1905 Nov 4] 6 p.; 1905 Nov 19 Postcard; [1905 Dec 19] 2 p.
    - [1907] 9 p.; [1907 May 30] 3 p.; [1907 Sep 15] 3 p.; [1907 Sep 23] 2 p.; [1908 Jun 2] 4 p.; 1908 Jul 24 1 p.
  - Envelopes from G. Kahn to FTM
    - n.d.; 1899 Apr 10; 1900 Aug 7; 1901 Feb 4; 1901 Mar 8; 1901 Sep 17; 1901 Nov 8 (Box 12, Folder 613)
    - 1901 Dec 12; 1902 Jan 16; 1904 Oct 7; 1904 Oct 13; 1905 Mar; 1905 Jul 4; 1905 Oct 16; 1905 Dec 19
    - 1906 Jan 9; 1907 May 18; 1907 Jun 7; 1907 Sep 26; 1909 Mar 16
      See also: Box 7, folder 69
  - Kahn, Rachel to FTM
    - [1907 Oct 19] 2 p. (Box 12, Folder 614)
      See also: Box 12, folder 612
  - Karahalios, Demetrio to FTM
    - 1925 Dec 17 2 p. TLS (Box 12, Folder 615)
  - Keller, Guido to FTM
    - n.d. "Per la citè future" cerca di conoscere... 3 p.; n.d. Adunata dei diciottisti Roma. premessa. ... 1 p. TLS; 1928 Oct 15 2 p. TLS (Box 12, Folder 616)
      See also: Series IV, Box 26, folder 1360
  - Kessler, Vanni to FTM
    - 1909 Aug 12 Postcard (Box 12, Folder 617)
  - Koch, Armando to FTM
    - 1926 Jun 12 3 p. (Box 12, Folder 618)
  - Koltinski, Alessandro to FTM
    - 1922 Oct 21 1 p. Underlining in blue pencil by FTM (Box 12, Folder 619)
  - Koltinski, Alessandro to Comitato Onoranze Marinetti
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram; signed Alessandro Koltinski Delegato Unione Letterati Polacchi (Box 12, Folder 620)
  - Koulbin, Nicolaj to FTM
    - 1914 Feb 27 Avez vous reçu nos télégrammes?... partly in Russian 4 p. (Box 12, Folder 621)
  - Kulturbund, Österreichische Gruppe des Verbandes Für Kulturelle Zusammenarbeit (Fédération des Unions Intellectuelles) to FTM
    - 1934 Oct 12 1 p. TLS; signed "La Gérante" (Jolande Jacoby?), on verso: pencil draft of a response in French in hand of FTM (Box 12, Folder 622)
  - Kurek [Wladyslaw] to FTM
    - 1924 Dec 30 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 623)
  - Labriola, Arturo to FTM
    - 1905 Oct 14 1 p. "R" on verso (Box 12, Folder 624)
  - La Croix, Riccardo to FTM
    - [1929 Mar] Card (Box 12, Folder 625)
  - Lattanzi to Segreteria Congresso Futurista
    - 1924 Nov 21 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 626)
  - Lecis, Riccardo to FTM
    - 1937 Sep 24 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 627)
  - du Leconty to FTM
    - n.d. Merci de votre intense... 2 p. (Box 12, Folder 628)
  - Lega,? A to FTM
    - 1910? Dec 2 1 p.; 1919 Jan 9 Postcard (Box 12, Folder 629)
  - Legrand-Chabrier to FTM
    - 1909 Jul 19 Postcard (Box 12, Folder 630)
  - Lerche, H. St. to FTM
    - 1909 Sep 17 Postcard (Box 12, Folder 631)
  - Leskovic, Michele (pseud. Escodamè) to FTM
    - No year Nov 19 Arrivato a Milano il 3 novembre... (Box 12, Folder 632)
      4 p.
  - Lettal, Salvatore to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 633)
  - La Lettura, Il Direttore to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 6 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 634)
  - Levaillant, Maurice to FTM
    - n.d. d'agrier ses vifs remerciements... Card (Box 12, Folder 635)
  - Levy to FTM
    - 1909 Aug 4 Postcard (Box 12, Folder 636)
  - Libani, E Ermanno to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 637)
  - Liguori, Renato to FTM
    - 1940 Jul 25 1 p. TLS; 1942 Aug 28 Postcard (Box 12, Folder 638)
  - Limoncelli, Mattia to Comitato Onoranze Marinetti
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 639)
  - Linarez, Luisa to Alberto Cappa
    - [1927 Sep 20] Postcard (Box 12, Folder 640)
  - Lipparini, Giuseppe to FTM
    - 1909 Nov 28 4 p.; 1922 Sep 27 Postcard; 1932 Apr 22 1 p.; 1939 Dec 30 2 p.; 1940 Jan 15 2 p. card; 1944 Apr 26 Postcard (Box 12, Folder 641)
  - Lischetti, M. to BCM
    - 1929 Dec 4 2 p. With receipt for 500 lire (Box 12, Folder 642)
  - Lo Duca to FTM
    - 1940 Sep 8 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 643)
  - Lomiry to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 644)
  - Lopresti, Salvator to Prampolini, Segretario Congresso Futurista
    - 1924 Nov 21 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 645)
  - Loria, Achille to FTM?
    - n.d. Card (Box 12, Folder 646)
  - Loti, Pierre to FTM
    - n.d. J'ai le culte passionné du passé... 3 p.; n.d. Avec ses meilleurs remerciements... Card; n.d. Je vous remercie de tout coeur... Postcard (Box 12, Folder 647)
  - Lovatelli, Bianca to BCM
    - 1944 Nov 4 (envelope has Dec 12) (Box 12, Folder 648)
  - Lovatelli, Filippo to BCM
    - 1937 Aug 14 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 649)
  - Loyson, Paul Hyacinthe to FTM
    - 1908 Jan 20 1 p. In French (Box 12, Folder 650)
  - Lozza, Arturo (Direttorio/Segretario Gruppo Arditi di Guerra del Fascio Milanese) to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 19 1 p. TLS (Box 12, Folder 651)
  - Lucanovich to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 24 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 652)
  - Lucchetti, Gino and Sascha to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 5 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 653)
  - Luciani, Francesco to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 654)
      See also: Box 8, folder 212
  - Lucini, Gian Pietro to FTM
    - 1909 Feb 5 3 p.; 1909 Feb 14 8 p.; 1909 Feb 25 3 p.; 1909 Jun 23 3 p.; 1910 Feb 17 2 p.; 1910 Mar 24 Postcard; 1910 Mar 28 Postcard (Box 12, Folder 655)
    - 1910 Apr 10 Postcard; 1910 May 8 3 p.; 1910 May 28 3 p.; 1910 May 30 4 p.; 1910 Jun 20 Postcard; 1910 Aug 16 Postcard; 1910 Oct 6 2 p.; 1910 Oct 18 Postcard
    - 1910 Dec 1 Postcard; 1910 Dec 23 Postcard; 1911 Jan 19 Postcard; 1911 Feb 28 Postcard; 1911 Mar 6 card; 1911 Apr 18 3 p.; 1911 May 12 3 p.; 1911 Jun 10 12 p.
  - Lucini, Gian Pietro to Boccioni, Umberto
    - 1910 Aug 30 10 p. On envelope, a pencil drawing of a face (Box 12, Folder 656)
  - Lucini, Gian Pietro to Cinti, Decio
    - 1912 Feb 10 Postcard (Box 12, Folder 657)
  - Lugli, Pilade to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 25 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 658)
  - Lugné-Poë, Aurélien-François to FTM
    - 1908 Nov 12 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 659)
  - Luongo, Giuseppe to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 15 2 p. (Box 12, Folder 660)
  - Lupattelli to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 661)
  - Luzzi to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 662)
  - Mac Delmarle, A.F. to FTM
    - 1918 Jan 25 2 p. in French (Box 12, Folder 663)
  - MacGill, Diana to Ente Artistico [Primo Congresso]
    - 1924 Nov 16 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 664)
  - Madia, Ugo to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 27 Telegram (Box 12, Folder 665)
  - Maestroni, Carmela to BCM
    - [1944 Dec 14] Card (Box 12, Folder 666)
  - Maeterlinck, Maurice to FTM
    - 1937 Oct 14 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 667)
  - Magamal to FTM
    - 1916 Oct 18 1 p.; 1918 Sep 9 4 p. (Box 12, Folder 668)
  - Maino, Angelo to FTM
    - 1922 Sep 6 1 p.; 1922 Sep 26 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 669)
  - Maino, Gigi (Segretario Politico, Partito Nazionale Fascista) to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 17 Card (Box 13, Folder 670)
  - Malaparte, Curzio to FTM
    - 1928 Dec 22 2 p.; 1929 May 13 2 p. (Box 13, Folder 671)
  - Malipiero, G. Francesco to FTM
    - 1922 Jun 19 6 p. (Box 13, Folder 672)
  - Mameli to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 673)
  - Mancini, Alfredo to FTM
    - 1909 Oct 13 Postcard (Box 13, Folder 674)
  - Mangano Maraffa, Lori to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 4 2 p. (Box 13, Folder 675)
  - Manni, Mario to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 676)
  - Mannoni, Remo (Altomare, Libero, pseud.) to FTM
    - 1909 Feb La vostra squisita bontà... 4 p;. 1910 May 6 1 p.; 1929 Mar 23 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 677)
  - Mansueti, Cesare to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 678)
  - Manzoni, Luigi to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 5 2 p. (Box 13, Folder 679)
  - "Mao" to Vittoria Marinetti
    - 1929 Aug 11 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 680)
  - Maraini, Antonio to FTM
    - 1937 Jul 15 1 p. TLS; Enclosures: 2 page printed letter about the Biennale di Venezia and a floor plan of the exhibition space.; 1940 Feb 3 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 681)
  - Marangoni, Guido to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 21 Card (Box 13, Folder 682)
  - Marangoni, Luigi to family of FTM
    - 1944 Dec 5 Card (Box 13, Folder 683)
  - Marasco, Antonio to Rougena Zátakova
    - [1922 May 29] Postcard; 1922 Jul 7 Postcard (Box 13, Folder 684)
  - Marasco, Antonio to FTM
    - 1923 Jan 2 3 p. with attached receipt; 1929 Mar 21 Telegram; 1942 Sep 9 2 p. (Box 13, Folder 685)
  - Maraviglia, Maurizio to FTM?
    - [1929? Mar?]. congratulazioni auguri affettuosi... Card (Box 13, Folder 686)
  - Marchesani, Guido to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 687)
  - Marchesi, Oreste to FTM
    - n.d. a l'uomo generoso-a l'apostolo-al... 2 p.; 1924 Nov 21 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 688)
  - Marchi, Virgilio to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 23 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 689)
  - Marchiandi to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 7 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 690)
  - Marcianti to FTM?
    - 1924 Nov 20 3 p. (Box 13, Folder 691)
  - Marconi, Guglielmo to FTM
    - 1931 Jan 26 1 p. TLS; 1937 Jan 5 1 p. TLS; 1937 Mar 2 Card (Box 13, Folder 692)
  - Maria, Princess of Piedmont to FTM
    - [1937? Feb?] 22 La ringrazio per suo poema... Telegram (Box 13, Folder 693)
  - Marinacci, Vincenzo to Congresso Futurista, Ente Italiano
    - 1924 Nov 14 1 p. Signed also by Osvaldo Rinonapoli (Box 13, Folder 694)
  - Marini, Mario to FTM
    - 1914 Jun 11 4 p. (Box 13, Folder 695)
  - Marino, Caleca
    See: Box 8, folder 236
  - Marinotti, Franco to FTM
    - 1937 Feb 27 2 p.; 1937 Aug 3 Card (Box 13, Folder 696)
  - Marinotti, Tina to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 3 Card (Box 13, Folder 697)
  - Marotta, Vincenzo to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 29 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 698)
  - Marraffa to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 26 2 p. (Box 13, Folder 699)
  - Martelli
  - Martin, Annabile to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 3 Card (Box 13, Folder 700)
  - Martino, Fausto M. to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 21 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 701)
  - Martinoso, L.
    See: BOx 8, folder 249
  - Marziali [Giovan Battista ,?] to FTM
    - 1938 Sep 10 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 702)
  - Masi, Nanni to FTM
    - 1915 Jan 27 Telegram siqned only "Masi", notes on verso (in hand of FTM).; (1929 Mar?) 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 703)
  - Masnata, Giovanni to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 25 Telegram; 1938 Jan 7 Telegram; 1939 May 31 1 p.; 1939 Jun? 13 Telegram; 1940 Jan 30 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 704)
  - Masnata, Isabella to BCM
    - 1940 Jan 27 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 705)
  - Masnata, Isabella to FTM
    - 1942 Jul 29 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 706)
  - Masnata, Pino to FTM
    - n.d. 1 p. Prescription or diagnosis with sketches in ink on verso.; 1929 Mar 22 Telegram; 1935 Jul 22 2 p.; 1939? May 14 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 707)
  - Masnata, Pino to BCM
    - [1936 Apr 2] 4 p.; 1942 Aug 12 3 p.; 1943 Mar 20 2 p.; 1944 Dec 3 2 p. Enclosure: 1 page ALS from Isabella Masnata; 1948 Dec 2 2 p. 1 page ALS from Isabella Masnata on page 2. (Box 13, Folder 708)
  - Massadi, Giovanni to FTM
    - 1905 May 24 3 p. (Box 13, Folder 709)
  - Massolo, Alfredo to Segretario, Primo Congresso Futurista Italiano
    - [1924?] 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 710)
  - Mastroveni, Matteo to FTM
    - 1922 Oct 25 3 p. (Box 13, Folder 711)
  - Matisse, Henri to FTM
    - 1942 Dec 24 2 p. In French (Box 13, Folder 712)
  - Empty folder (Box 13, Folder 713)
  - Mattoli
    See: Box 15, folder 903
  - Mauclair, Camille to FTM
    - [1904?] Apr 7 2 p. In French; 1904 Nov 22 7 p. In French; 1908 Feb 4 2 p. In French (Box 13, Folder 714)
  - Maurizio to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 715)
  - Mayer, Aldo to Umberto Notari
    - 1934 Apr 11 1 p. TLS (Box 13, Folder 716)
  - Mayhew, Sue (Illustrations Research, The Hamlyn Group, UK) to BCM
    - 1970 Jul 22 1 p. TLS In English (Box 13, Folder 717)
  - Mazza to FTM
    - 1940 Feb 28 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 718)
  - Mazza, Aldo to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 20 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 719)
  - Mazza, Armando to Umberto Notari
    - 1934 May 5 1 p. Enclosure: 1 page TLS of a list of contributors to a gift for FTM, from Mazza to Notari (Box 13, Folder 720)
  - Mazza, Armando to FTM
    - 1935 Sep 6 1 p.; 1939 Dec 5 1 p. card (Box 13, Folder 721)
  - Mazzi, Ruggero to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 1 p. TLS (Box 13, Folder 722)
  - Mazzinghi, Mario to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 723)
  - Mazzolini, Serafino to FTM
    - 1938 Apr 3 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 724)
  - Mazzolini, Serafino to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 2 Telegram; 1944 Dec 3 Telegram; accompanied by a telegram to Ministro Bonarelli with message for BCM from Japanese Ambassador Hidaka.; 1944 Dec 7 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 724a)
  - Mazzolotti, Piero to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 2 1 p. TLS (Box 13, Folder 725)
  - Mazzoni
    See: Box 7, folder 138
  - Mazzoni, A[ngelo?] to BCM
    - 1931 Apr 20 Postcard (Box 13, Folder 726)
  - Mazzoni, Guido to FTM
    - 1909 Aug 4 Card (Box 13, Folder 727)
  - Mazzotti, Giuseppe to FTM
    - 1939 Apr 22 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 728)
  - Mazzotti, Tullio (D'Albisola, Tullio, pseud.) to FTM
    - 1934 Apr 9 1 p. TLS; "R" written in pencil (by FTM?); 1935 Jul 17 1 p. TLS; 1942 Aug 29 Postcard; signed also by Zucco, Walter Ferrato, Piera Stemfity, Mareu..., Rosy Piera, Noeni Carelli.; 1942 Aug 31 1 p. TLS; signed also by Vittoria, Esa, and one other (Box 13, Folder 729)
  - Mazzotti, Tullio (D'Albisola, Tullio, pseud.) to BCM
    - 1943 Mar 6 1 p. TLS; 1944 Dec 2 2 p. (Box 13, Folder 730)
  - Mazzotti, Tullio (D'Albisola, Tullio, pseud.) to Umberto Notari
    - 1934 May 7 1 p. TLS (Box 13, Folder 731)
  - Mazzotti, Tullio (D'Albisola, Tullio, pseud.) to Giuseppe Rosso
    - 1937 May 27 1 p. TLS (Box 13, Folder 732)
  - Mazzucchetti, A to FTM?
    - No year Aug 4 Vi sono grato di esservi... Card (Box 13, Folder 733)
  - Mei, Lea to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 734)
  - Meissner, H.O. to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 2 1 p. TLS (Box 13, Folder 735)
  - Menasci, Guido to FTM
    - 1909 Aug 6 Card (Box 13, Folder 736)
  - Mendès, Catulle to FTM
    - 1907 Dec 2 Telegram In French (Box 13, Folder 737)
  - Menin, G. to FTM
    - 1937 Oct 1 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 738)
  - Menin, Mario to FTM
    - n.d. ho ritrovato una tempera dipinta... 2 p.; 1943 Jun 17 3 p. (Box 13, Folder 739)
  - Meriano, [Francesco?] to FTM
    - 1922 Aug 10 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 740)
      See also: Box 8, folder 178
  - Merrill, Stuart to FTM
    - 1908 Feb 4 - 5 p. In French. "R" in blue pencil on envelope (Box 13, Folder 741)
  - Messe, Giovanni to unidentified recipient
    - n.d. No message Card (Box 13, Folder 742)
  - Messina, Bianca and Francesco to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 2 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 743)
  - Mezzasoma, Fernando to FTM
    - [1942] Telegram (Box 13, Folder 744)
      See also: Box 12, folder 597
  - Miceli, Peppino to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 31 Postcard (Box 13, Folder 745)
  - Michahelles, Ernesto (Thayaht, Ernesto, pseud.) to FTM
    - 1939 Apr 15 1 p. TLS; accompanied by a clipping: "La nascita di Leonardo". (Box 13, Folder 746)
  - Michelet, Victor-Emile to FTM
    - 1909 Jul 25 1 p. In French (Box 13, Folder 747)
  - Mieli, Clara to BCM
    - [1944] Dec 2 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 748)
  - Mieli, Lide to BCM
    - [1944] Dec 3 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 749)
  - Migliore to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 21 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 750)
  - Millevoye to [FTM?]
    - 1909 Jul 25 1 p. In French (Box 13, Folder 751)
  - Mitzitch, Lioubomir to FTM
    - 1926 Dec 17 Telegram; 1926 Dec 22 Telegram; from a lawyer, De Sachs, requesting FTM's aid for Mitzitch's release from prison; 1926 Dec 25 1 p. In French; 1926 Dec 25 Telegram In French; [1940?] Feb 6 Le sang zenitiste sauvra... Telegram In French (Box 13, Folder 752)
  - Mizza, S.R. to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 23 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 753)
  - Mocenigo, Costanza To BCM
    - n.d. Ti scrissi lungamente giorne 2 p. card Signed Onestina; [1944] Dec 3 2 p. Signed Onestina; 1944 Dec 4 4 p. (Box 13, Folder 754)
  - Mocke, Albert to FTM
    - 1905 Jul 30 Postcard In French (Box 13, Folder 755)
  - Moissy, Gabriel to FTM
    - 1938 Sep 27 2 p. In French (Box 13, Folder 756)
  - Molinari, Luciano to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 25 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 757)
  - Moma,? Mario to FTM
    - 1940 Oct 2 2 p. (Box 13, Folder 758)
  - Momigliani to FTM
    - 1938 Oct 27 1 p. "Momigliani," written in orange pencil in hand of FTM at bottom of page (Box 13, Folder 759)
  - Monachesi, Sante to FTM
    - 1938 Nov 2 1 p. TLS; his address and that of Tano written under the signature, possibly in the hand of FTM (Box 13, Folder 760)
  - Mondadori, Arnoldo to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram; 1932 Jun 11 2 p. TLS ;1939 Sep 25 1 p. TLS; 1942 Feb 5 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 761)
  - Montagna, G.C. to FTM
    - 1926 Jun 2 3 p.; 1926 Jul 22 4 p.; 1926 Nov 21 4 p.; 1929 Mar 22 2 p. (Box 13, Folder 762)
  - Montagna, G.C. to le R.R. Autorità Doganali di Genova
    1926 Jul 12 1 p. TLS
  - Montalto, Giuseppe to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 26 Telegram; 1929 Apr 2 Postcard (Box 13, Folder 763)
  - Montemassi to FTM
    - [1929 Mar] 22 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 764)
  - Morandi, Guglielmo to FTM
    - 1911 Mar 30 Postcard (Box 13, Folder 765)
  - Moréas, Jean to FTM
    1905 Oct 4 3 p. In French, all pages glued together to make one sheet; "Corsivo 10" written in blue pencil, in hand of FTM?
    See: Oversize, Box 54, folder 1999
  - Moretti, Marino to FTM
    - 1910 ? 25 4 p.; 1931 Nov 5 1 p. (Box 13, Folder 766)
  - Morgagni, Bice to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 6 2 p. (Box 13, Folder 767)
  - Morgagni, Manlio to Comitato Onoranze Marinetti
    - 1924 Nov 22? Telegram (Box 13, Folder 768)
  - Morgagni, Manlio to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 21 1 p. card (Box 13, Folder 769)
  - Morisi, Celso to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 24 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 770)
  - Morreale to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 21 Telegram (Box 13, Folder 771)
  - Morselli to FTM
    - 1908 Jan 17 Postcard; 1909 Aug 6 Postcard (Box 14, Folder 772)
  - Mortari, Virgilio to FTM?
    - 1924 Nov 9 Card (Box 14, Folder 773)
  - Mortier, Alfred to FTM
    - 1909 Jul 15 1 p. In French (Box 14, Folder 774)
  - Mortier, Mme. Aurélie (de Faucamberge) [Aurel, pseud.] to FTM
    - [1908 Jul? 9] 4 p. In French; 1930 Jun 25 2 p. (Box 14, Folder 775)
  - Mory, A.G. to FTM
    - 1909 Jul 13 1 p. In French (Box 14, Folder 776)
  - Mucci, Renato to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 23 Telegram (Box 14, Folder 777)
  - Müller, Béla to FTM
    - 1928 Mar 22 4 p. Notes in hand of FTM, p. 4. (Box 14, Folder 778)
  - Munari, Bruno to FTM
    - 1940 Feb 4 Telegram (Box 14, Folder 779)
  - Musco, Vincenzo (Etna, Giacomo, pseud.) to Ente Artistico [Primo Congresso Futurista]
    - 1924 Nov 13 Postcard (Box 14, Folder 780)
  - Musco, Vincenzo to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 22 Telegram (Box 14, Folder 781)
  - Mussolini, Arnaldo to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 21 Telegram (Box 14, Folder 782)
  - Mussolini, Benito to FTM
    - 1923 Mar 2 p. 1924; Nov 22 Telegram; 1928 Oct 27 1 p.; 1929 Mar 21 Telegram; 1929 Sep 27 Telegram; 1929 Oct 30 Telegram; 1931 Dec 25 Telegram (All signed "Mussolini" only) (Box 14, Folder 783)
  - Mussolini, Bruno to FTM
    - 1938 Nov 25 Telegram; signed by Gina and Bruno Mussolini (Box 14, Folder 784)
  - Napoletano, Aldo to FTM
    - [1929 Mar] 1 p. (Box 14, Folder 785)
  - Nassi to BCM
    - 1928 Apr 13 1 p. (Box 14, Folder 786)
  - Nebbia, Ugo to FTM
    - 1929 Mar 25 1 p. (Box 14, Folder 787)
  - Nebbia, Ugo to BCM
    - [1944] Dec 3 1 p. (Box 14, Folder 788)
  - Negri, Ada to FTM
    - n.d. Tutto il giorno la bella creatura... 1 p. Poem entitled "La maschera"; No year Mar 22 Postcard; signed also by Anselini.; 1905 May 3 p. Poem entitled "Rose rosse"; "c.10 frame" written in blue pencil on p. 1 in hand of FTM; 1905 Mar 16 4 p. (Box 14, Folder 789)
    - 1905 Apr 4 Postcard; 1905 May 2 2 p. card; 1905 May 31 Card signed Ada Negri Garlanda.; 1905 Aug 4 2 p.; 1905 Sep 12 4 p.; 1905 Nov 19 3 p.; 1906 May 19 Card
    - 1906 Jun 24 3 p.; 1906 Aug 8 Postcard; 1906 Oct 26 1 p.; 1906 Oct 30 1 p. "R" written in blue pencil on envelope.; 1906 Dec 1 2 p. "R" in blue pencil on verso.; 1907 Jan 11 3 p. "R" in blue pencil on verso.; 1908 May 16 2 p.
    - 1908 Aug 20 3 p.; 1908 Oct 20 1 p.; 1909 Aug 31 2 p.; 1910 May 2 3 p.; 1912 Dec 2 3 p.; 1921 Jun 16 2 p.; 1930 Mar 23 1 p. Large vertical tear on left side
    - 1933 Jul 26 Postcard; 1939 Mar 9 2 p. card; 1942 Jan 14 2 p.; 1942 Sep 22 3 p.
  - Negri, Ada to BCM
    - 1928 Dec 29 1 p.; 1943 Jan 16 2 p.; 1943 Mar 4 Postcard; 1943 Mar 10 2 p.; 1944 Dec 3 1 p. (Box 14, Folder 790)
  - Negri, Ada to Comitato Onoranze Marinetti
    - 1924 Nov 23 Telegram (Box 14, Folder 791)
  - Niccodemi, Dario to FTM
    - n.d. Saturday 5 Je recois ici votre envoi... 2 p. card (Box 14, Folder 792)
  - Nicefora, Mario to Comitato Onoranze a FTM
    - 1924 Nov 9 Postcard (Box 14, Folder 793)
  - Nicotera, Alessandro to FTM
    - 1924 Nov 23 Telegram (Box 14, Folder 794)
  - Nigro, (Sorelle) to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 3 Card (Box 14, Folder 795)
  - Ninette to BCM
    - 1944 Dec 5 2 p. card (Box 14, Folder 796)
  - Nitti, A. to FTM
    - 1909 Nov 1 8 p. (Box 14, Folder 797)
  - Noailles, Anna de to FTM
    - n.d. Vous ai écrit hier reçois... Telegram; n.d. Voici la première pièce de vers... 3 p.; n.d. Mercredi 2 Voici les vers qui étaient déjà... 2 p.; 1905 Enthousiaste et remercie admirables... Telegram; 1905 Lettre expédiée hier... Telegram; 1905 ? 29 Vous expedie poème... Telegram (Box 14, Folder 798)
    - [1905 Feb 27] 4 p.; 1905 Apr 4 Postcard; 1905 Apr 5 Postcard; [1905] Sep 3 1 p.; 1906 Jan 9 Telegram; "R" in blue pencil on verso; [1906 Apr 10] 6 p. "R" in blue pencil on envelope.; 1907 Jan 7 Postcard Signed by Noailles, written in a different hand
  - Noailles, Anna de to Madame Ipadre?
    - 1906 Oct 18 4 p. (Box 14, Folder 799)
  - Nobile, Fernanda to FTM
    - 1940 Feb 26 Telegram (Box 14, Folder 800)
  - Noè, Torrietto
  - Norano, Angiolo Silvio to FTM
    - 1904 Oct 22 3 p. (Box 14, Folder 801)
  - Nosari, Adone to Comitato Onoranze a FTM
    - 1924 Nov 22 Telegram (Box 14, Folder 802)
  - Notari, Delia to BCM
    - 1925 Apr 1 Telegram; [1926 Mar 9] 3 p.; 1926 Mar 17 Telegram; also addressed to FTM. (Box 14, Folder 803)
  - Notari, Umberto to FTM
    - 1918 Nov 14 1 p. TLS; signed also by Delia Notari; 1929 Mar 22 Telegram; signed also by Delia Notari; 1935 May 31 1 p.; 1942 Sep 10 3 p. (Box 14, Folder 804)
  - Notari, Umberto to BCM
    - 1930 Sep 1 Telegram; 1944 Dec 29 2 p. (Box 14, Folder 805)
  - Notaro, Domenico to BCM
    - [1944] Dec 3 1 p. (Box 14, Folder 806)